{"tossups": [{"question": "The \"Zaarin\" aspect of this deity appears as a spirit who gives Khorchi a vision of a cow stating an ancestor of his will be a great leader. To the Uyghur people, the Chinese Tian Shan range is instead named for this deity. Uzbeg Khan's conversion to Islam led to his renunciation of a faith named for this god, and prior to battle, the Huns sacrificed horses to this chief deity in return for victory. For the point, name this sky-god of various medieval Turkic and Mongolic people.", "answer": "<b><u>Tengri</u></b> (or <b><u>Tenjiri</u></b>; accept <b><u>Tengri</u></b>sm)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "One man of this first name was banished to Flanders after being put in chains by his brother Eric Evergood. The starvation faced by both the rich and poor under that man\u2019s reign led him to be nicknamed \u201cHunger\". Another leader of this name was a successor of Sweyn [[SVANE]] Forkbeard and received his confirmation in Andover at the hands of Ethelred the Unready. A statue in Trondheim commemorates that king of this name referred to as Tryggvason [[trig-VAH-sun]]. For the point, give this name shared by numerous kings and the patron saint of Norway.", "answer": "<b><u>Olaf</u></b> (accept <b><u>Olav</u></b>; accept <b><u>Olaf</u></b> Hunger; accept <b><u>Olaf</u></b> I; accept <b><u>Olaf</u></b> II; accept <b><u>Olaf</u> </b>Tryggvason)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This commander of the 9th Mechanized Corps conducted the only significant counter-attack during Operation Barbarossa by initiating a tank battle at Brody. After World War Two, this man was made Defence Minister in an occupied country until he was dismissed by Secretary Gomulka. During the war, Stalin called this man his \"Bagration\" after the success of an operation of that name, however this general was excluded from the assault on Berlin due to his Polish ancestry. For the point, name this Marshal of the Soviet Union and contemporary of Semyon Timoshenko and Georgy Zhukov.", "answer": "Konstantin <b><u>Rokassovsky</u></b> (or Konstantin Konstantinovich (Xaverevich) <b><u>Rokassovsky</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The name of this period was coined by Edward S. Morse, who received a large donation of pottery artifacts now found in the Museum of Fine Arts in Boston. In the north, this period was succeeded by the Okhotsk and Satsumon cultures. This period is named for its cord-marked pottery, which includes the large-eyed dog\u016b figurines. This period's namesake hunter-gatherers were supplanted by the agricultural Yayoi [[yah-YOH]] people. For the point, name this prehistoric period of Japanese history, which extended from roughly 14,000 to 400 B.C.", "answer": "<b><u>Jomon</u></b> Period (accept <b><u>J\u014dmon</u></b> jidai; accept <b><u>Jomon</u></b> culture or people; accept \"Era\" in place of \"Period\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Though not involving Nigeria, William Rooke\u2019s force was defeated at this war\u2019s Battle of Lagos. This conflict was prompted by the breaking of what was supposed to be a 20-year peace in the fourth year after the Treaty of Ratisbon ended the War of the Reunions. St. Kitts changed hands multiple times during this conflict, whose peace treaty was stalled by questions over the succession of the childless Spanish king Charles II. The 1697 Peace of Ryswick ended this conflict. For the point, name this conflict involving a coalition opposing France.", "answer": "<b><u>Nine Years\u2019 War</u></b> (accept War of the <b><u>League of Augsburg</u></b>; accept War of the <b><u>Grand Alliance</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "At a non-Punic Battle of Cannae [[kah-NAY]], the arrival of members of this group helped cement the defeat of Melus of Bari. Members of this group often wore red rubies in their left ear as well as dragon decorations in their chainmail. They attacked fleeing members of Bardas Phokas\u2019 army after Phokas died of a stroke and were described in <em>The</em> <em>Alexiad</em> as mounted soldiers. Originally chosen from among the Rus, its members wielded the Dane Axe. Often composed of tall Norsemen, for the point, what is this elite unit that defended the Byzantine Emperor?", "answer": "<b><u>Varangian Guard</u></b> (accept <b><u>T\u00e1gma t\u014dn Var\u00e1ng\u014dn</u></b>; prompt on <b><u>Byzantine Guard</u></b>s or similar answers)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man, who was never elected to public office, lost the 1934 race for governor of New York as the Republican nominee. This man's reputation was damaged by the Pulitzer-winning 1974 Robert Caro biography, <em>The Power Broker</em>. Some of this man\u2019s projects include the construction of the New York campuses for the 1939 and 1964 World\u2019s Fair, and this man helped persuade the UN to place its headquarters in Manhattan. For the point, name this public official known as the \u201cMaster Builder\u201d of mid-20th century New York City.", "answer": "Robert <b><u>Moses</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This author wrote a play set around the Night of the Long Knives, <em>My Friend Hitler</em>, as a mouthpiece for his own fascist sympathies. This man's work <em>Runaway Horses</em> is set in the wake of the May 15th Incident by the reactionary <em>Ketsumei-dan</em> led by Nissh\u014d Inoue [[eh-new-EH]]. This writer and his fellow members of the <em>Tatenokai</em> [[tah-TEH-noh-KYE]] committed <em>seppuku</em> on live television after a failed coup attempt to restore the emperor Hirohito to his previous authority. For the point, name this Japanese writer of <em>The Temple of</em> <em>Golden Pavilion</em> and <em>Confessions of a Mask</em>.", "answer": "<b><u>Mishima</u></b> Yukio (or Kimitake <b><u>Hiraoka</u></b>; or <b><u>Hiraoka</u></b> Kimitake; accept Yukio <b><u>Mishima</u></b>)", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "This man successfully defended Gaius Julius Bassus from allegations of embezzlement while serving in Nicomedia [[NIH-koh-MEE-dee-ah]]. This man likely employed the historian and family friend Suetonius [[SOO-eh-TOH-nee-us]] in his administration while serving in a proconsulship in Northwestern Anatolia. As a young man, he chronicled the death of his uncle, who is known by the same name, in the aftermath of the 79 CE eruption of Vesuvius. For the point, name this Roman magistrate known for his <em>Epistulae</em> [[eh-PIH-styoo-lay]], which include his personal correspondence with Emperor Trajan.", "answer": "<b><u>Pliny</u></b> the Younger (or Gaius <b><u>Plinius</u></b> Caecilius Secundus; do not accept or prompt on \"Pliny the Elder\")", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "A 1971 Sorcery Act passed by this nation's parliament banned black magic, with over a hundred men and women dying annually from accusations of witchcraft. A type of encephalopathy named <em>kuru</em> is common among the Fore [[\"foray\"]] tribe of this nation due to their practice of funerary cannibalism. This Asian nation, which uses the creole \"Tok Pisin,\" was once split into German and British dominated spheres. For the point, name this nation once administered by its neighbor across the Torres Strait, Australia.", "answer": "<b><u>Papua New Guinea</u></b> (or <b><u>Papuaniugini</u></b>; prompt on \"Papua\"; do not accept or prompt on \"New Guinea\" or \"Guinea\")", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "A study titled \u201cThis Sudden Spasm of Newspaper Hostility\u201d chronicles the stereotyping of this ethnic group in Boston. One member of this ethnic group spent 28 years secretly creating a structure made of oolite found in Dade County. Coral Castle was built by a member of this ethnicity, whose famous members include painter Mark Rothko and the inventor of denim jeans, Jacob Davis. Many immigrants of this ethnicity fled during the interwar tenure of dictator K\u0101rlis Ulmanis. Often called Letts, for the point, what is this group of Baltic immigrants from cities like Riga?", "answer": "<b><u>Latvia</u></b>n-Americans (accept <b><u>Lett</u></b>s or <b><u>Lettish</u></b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this campaign, the pocket battleship <em>Admiral Graf Spee</em> was scuttled in Montevideo harbor. This campaign included Operation <em>Rhein\u00fcbung</em>, which culminated in the sinking of the <em>Bismarck</em> by the HMS <em>King George V</em> and the HMS <em>Prince of Wales</em>. This naval campaign began its \u201cSecond Happy Time\u201d after the United States entered the war, leading to Karl D\u00f6nitz\u2019s [[DER-nits]] innovation of the \u201cWolf Pack\u201d U-Boat strategy. For the point, name this six-year naval campaign on the namesake ocean during World War Two.", "answer": "Battle of the <b><u>Atlantic</u></b> (accept Battle of the <b><u>River Plate</u></b> before \"Rhein\u00fcbung\": prompt on the \"The Happy Time\" or \"\"Die Gl\u00fcckliche Zeit\" before \"Happy Time\" is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This city is home to secret passageways called <em>traboules</em>. The Year of the Five Emperors ended after a 197 CE battle in this city where Clodius Albinus lost to Septimius Severus. The <em>canuts</em> [[kah-NOO]] revolted against King Louis-Philippe over poor treatment at silk workshops in this city, which the Romans called Lugdunum. Because he tortured prisoners at the Gestapo headquarters in this city\u2019s Hotel Terminus, Klaus Barbie was nicknamed its \u201cButcher.\u201d For the point, name this city on the Rhone, the third-largest in France after Paris and Marseille.", "answer": "<b><u>Lyon</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Lugdunum</u></b> until mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Charles Rosen claims that a portion of a work dedicated to this man, which features a six-voice ricercar, is the most significant piano work ever. This man wrote 120 sonatas for the transverse variety of one instrument. This dedicatee of <em>The Musical Offering</em> commemorated one of his military victories in the <em>Hohenfriedberger March</em>. Adolph Menzel portrayed this man's flute concert in Potsdam. For the point, name this Prussian monarch and proponent of the Enlightenment.", "answer": "<b><u>Frederick</u></b> the <b><u>Great</u></b> (accept <b><u>Frederick II</u></b>; accept <b><u>Friedrich</u></b> in place of Frederick; prompt on partial answer)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Trade unions in what is now this country opposed the seizure of power by Saye Zerbo. A leader of this country\u2019s Committees for the Defense of the Revolution was often referred to as \u201cAfrica\u2019s Che Guevara.\u201d That leader from this country carried out a series of Popular Revolutionary Tribunals against \u201clazy\u201d officials. Blaise Compaor\u00e9 [[kahm-pow-REH]] was a longtime president of this country, whose majority ethnic group is the Mossi. This country was once known as the Republic of the Upper Volta. For the point, name this landlocked country which was ruled by Thomas Sankara.", "answer": "<b><u>Burkina Faso</u></b> (prompt on \"Upper Volta\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Henry Davis was on one ticket in this election year, which was the second in which Eugene Debs ran. Alton B. Parker was defeated in this election year, though he won the entire South despite being a New Yorker like his opponent. This was the first ever election year in which a vice-president-turned-president won, having done so after the assassination three years prior of William McKinley. For the point, name this election year in which Theodore Roosevelt won the presidency.", "answer": "<b><u>1904</u></b> United States presidential election", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "It's not scoria, but this good was meant to act as the pupils of the <em>Moai</em> [[MOH-\"eye\"]] statues created by the Rapa Nui. The Aztec <em>Macuahuitl</em> [[mah-kwah-HWEH-til]] was a wooden club with blades made of this sharp mineral embedded on its side. This mineral, which takes its name from the Roman explorer who first described it in the Ethiopian highlands, was used by the Polynesian Lapita to make glass knives. For the point, name this volcanic glass made from the rapid cooling of felsic lava.", "answer": "<b><u>Obsidian</u></b> (prompt on \"volcanic glass\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "A battle in this state involved a flanking attack on a supply train that was inflicted at Johnson\u2019s Ranch. The aforementioned \u201cGettysburg of the West\u201d occurred in this state in the Sangre de Cristo Mountains. The Battle of Glorieta Pass occurred on a trail linking one of this state's major cities to Franklin, Missouri. The Mountain Route of that trail passed near this state's city of Taos. For the point, name this state that was home to the westernmost terminus of the Santa Fe Trail.", "answer": "<b><u>New Mexico</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "According to Al-Tabari, a ruler of these people impressed dinner guests by cleaning his napkin coated with asbestos by throwing it into the fire. That ruler of this empire, known as \"The Victorious,\" was briefly usurped by general Bahram Chobin in the midst of a White Huns invasion in the 590s. An invasion of this nation by the Byzantine emperor Heraclius ravaged much of Mesopotamia, including its capital of Ctesiphon [[TEH-seh-fawn]], leading to the deposition of this empire's shah, Khosrow II [[kaws-ROH]]. For the point, name this Persian empire of the early Middle Ages which displaced the Parthians in the 3rd Century.", "answer": "<b><u>Sasanian</u></b> Empire (accept <b><u>Sassanid</u></b>s or <b><u>Sassanid</u></b> Empire; accept <b><u>Empire of</u></b> <b><u>Iranians</u></b>; accept <b><u>Neo-Persian</u></b> Empire or <b><u>Neo-Persian</u></b>s before \"Persia\" is mentioned; )", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The Supreme Akali Party led demonstrations during this event known as the \"Campaign to Save Democracy.\" The <em>Nasbandi</em> campaign was undertaken during this historical period, leading to the forced sterilization of millions of peasants. While a member of the paramilitary RSS, Narendra Modi dressed as a Sikh during this period to avoid arrest without trial. For the point, name this suspension of civil liberties in 1970s India ordered by sitting Prime Minister Indira Gandhi.", "answer": "The <b><u>Emergency</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A senator from this state named John P. Hale co-founded the Free Soil Party, later losing the 1852 nomination for its presidential candidate to Martin van Buren. This state nearly merged with Quebec after they held a convention with British officials during the Revolutionary War, and it was known to early Americans as the \"Reluctant Republic.\" A force led, in part, by Seth Warner captured this state's Fort Ticonderoga. For the point, name this state whose Green Mountain Boys were commanded by Ethan Allen.", "answer": "<b><u>Vermont</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Fitzhugh Lee served as Consul-General during this event, which involved a Theodore Wilson-designed object made of Harvey steel. Francis W. Dickins called this event an accident, and the <em>City of Washington</em> rescued people after this event. The Sampson Board investigated this event, as did Hyman Rickover, though a proposed joint investigation into this event was planned to include Spanish authorities. For the point, name this explosion of a ship in Havana harbor, one cause of the Spanish-American War.", "answer": "Explosion of the USS <em><b><u>Maine</u></b></em> (accept \"Accident,\" \"Sinking,\" or similar descriptions in place of \"Explosion\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man sent George Washington a letter from the disgruntled Benjamin Rush, thus warning Washington of the Conway Cabal. This man's biography was written by William Wirt. This attorney marched his troops to Williamsburg to stop Governor Dunmore from taking gunpowder. This man refused to attend the Constitutional Convention, stating \"I smelt a rat.\" A phrase from this man might have been inspired by the play <em>Cato: A Tragedy</em> or <em>Artemisia</em>. For the point, name this Founding Father who said \"Give me liberty, or give me death!\"", "answer": "Patrick <b><u>Henry</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Genetic testing suggests that some residents of Lamu Island are descendants of participants in these events. The route of these events is preserved in the Mao Kun Map. In his book <em>1421</em>, Gavin Menzies controversially claimed that the participants in these events arrived in the Americas decades before Columbus. These events involved the construction and use of the largest ever junk ships. For the point, name these Chinese expeditions commissioned by the Yongle [[YAWNG-LUH]] Emperor, which were led by a Muslim eunuch.", "answer": "<b><u>Ming Treasure Voyages</u></b> (accept <b><u>Zheng He's Expeditions</u></b>; accept <b><u>Zheng He Xia</u></b> <b><u>Xiyang</u></b>; accept descriptive answers indicating <b><u>Ming</u></b> Dynasty or <b><u>Zheng He</u></b>'s travels to attain treasure)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Roger Khan, a leader of one of these organizations, paid for an advertisement in Guyana which claimed his \"Phantom Death Squad\" was more effective than the local police. Ecuadorian authorities seized several submarines operated by these specific organizations, who intended to smuggle goods into Mexico and the United States. El Mayo, a leader of these organizations headquartered in Sinaloa, took over after the 2014 arrest of \"El Chapo.\" Pablo Escobar headed the Medellin [[med-eh-YEEN]] iteration of, for the point, what type of criminal organization which traffics illicit substances?", "answer": "Drug <b><u>Cartel</u></b>s (accept Drug <b><u>Traffic</u></b>king Organizations)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "A statue at Annapolis bears this man's name, although it actually depicts Tamanend. James Drain claimed that William Whitley killed this man, though Richard Mentor Johnson often gets the credit for doing so at the Battle of the Thames [[TEMZ]]. This man tried to end land cession treaties by rescinding the Treaty of Fort Wayne. The Great Comet of 1811 was seen as an omen of good luck for this man's allies. Founding Prophetstown with Tenskwatawa [[TEN-skweh-TOE-way]], for the point, what Shawnee leader's forces were defeated at Tippecanoe?", "answer": "<b><u>Tecumseh</u></b> (accept <b><u>Tamanend</u></b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Christian symbol of foot-washing is used by Johannes Vermeer to depict this non-Christian Latin deity in a painting where she is accompanied by her <em>Nymphs</em>. Francesco Solimena exemplified platonic love in a painting where this goddess lusts for her unrequited love, Endymion [[en-DIH-mee-on]]. Philip II of Spain commissioned a painting by Titian which depicts this goddess transfiguring Actaeon into a stag and being devoured by his own hounds. For the point, name this Roman Goddess often depicted as a \"Huntress\" in visual arts.", "answer": "<b><u>Diana</u></b> (do not accept or prompt on \"Artemis\")", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Two weeks before this event, Bernard Coard was appointed Deputy Prime Minister for just six days. This event resulted in the deposition of Hudson Austin, leader of the New Jewel Movement. This event, which led to the restoration of parliamentary democracy under Herbert Blaize, caused the deaths of Jacqueline Creft and a Marxist-Leninist who earlier removed Eric Gairy from office, Maurice Bishop. For the point, name this Reagan-era military action in which the U.S. toppled the government of a Caribbean island.", "answer": "United States <b><u>Invasion</u></b> of <b><u>Grenada</u></b> (accept Operation <b><u>Urgent Fury</u></b>; accept similar words for <b><u>invasion</u></b> such as <b><u>attack</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "City or year accepted. In this Olympics, Belarusian gymnast Vitaly Scherbo [[SHEHR-boh]] won six gold medals. Christian Laettner was the only collegiate player on a dominant team in this Olympics that beat Croatia by 32 points in its championship game. Although they were runners-up in the Winter Olympics in Albertville the same year, the Unified Team won the most medals at this Olympics. Fears that the ETA would bomb this Olympics proved to be unfounded. Larry Bird and Michael Jordan played on the \u201cDream Team\u201d in, for the point, what Summer Olympics held in Spain?", "answer": "19<b><u>92</u></b> Summer Olympics (accept the <b><u>Barcelona</u></b> Olympics; accept either underlined portion of <b><u>Barcelona</u><u>92</u></b>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "In the 3rd Century, the Hohokam people native to the area around this modern city built the largest pre-Columbian irrigation system using handheld tools. This city's founder, a Confederate minuteman named Jack Swilling, died while awaiting trial for robbing a stagecoach in Wickenburg. Barry Goldwater's first political post was on this city's council, and it lies on the northeastern reaches of the Sonoran Desert. For the point, name this city in Maricopa County, the capital and largest city of Arizona.", "answer": "<b><u>Phoenix</u></b> (accept the Navajo <b><u>Hoozdo</u></b>)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "One of these structures named for its resemblance to a serpent is located near an impact crater in Ohio. Some of the oldest of these structures are found in Poverty Point, and the Hopewell and Adena people built these structures. St. Louis once had many of these structures before European settlement, and the largest of these structures, now named for monks, is located in Cahokia, Illinois. For the point, identify these structures which name a Pre-Columbian culture of the Mississippi River Basin.", "answer": "<b><u>Mound</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Earthwork</u></b>s)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "A survey similar to William the Conqueror's Domesday [[\"Doomsday\"]] Book that was undertaken by this king, and was known as the Hundred Rolls. With Leo II of Armenia, this king warred with Baibars while still holding the title of Duke of Gascony. Andrew Moray died from wounds sustained fighting against this king, who was victorious at the Battle of Falkirk. Eleanor of Castile married this man, who is thought to have solidified Parliament as a permanent entity and oversaw the expulsion of Jews starting in the late 13th century. For the point, identify this King of England nicknamed \u201cLongshanks\u201d and the \"Hammer of the Scots.\"", "answer": "<b><u>Edward I</u></b> of England (accept <b><u>Edward Longshanks</u></b> or <b><u>Edward, Hammer of the</u></b> <b><u>Scots</u></b>; prompt on partial answer)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This Texas-based company, once a division of Barnes & Noble named Funco, went public in 2002. Nearly two decades later, a short squeeze led to a 1,500 percent increase in this company\u2019s share price over a mere two weeks. A financial investment firm named Robinhood outraged small investors when it suddenly restricted the trading of this company\u2019s shares. For the point, what videogame retail chain, stock symbol GME, was the focus of the investing world in the winter of 2021?", "answer": "<b><u>GameStop</u></b> Corp. (accept <b><u>GME</u></b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "A singer from this country named Cheb Khaled wrote a famous song about one of its freedom fighters in its native Ra\u00ef style. Members of this country\u2019s tribes were originally intended to be members of <em>zouave</em> [[ZHWAHV]] regiments. In this country, Houari Boum\u00e9di\u00e8ne [[boo-MEH-dee-EN]] came to power after toppling Ahmed Ben Bella, who led its FLN party. Many <em>pied-noirs</em> left this country during its struggle for independence, which was achieved via the \u00c9vian Accords. For the point, name this country which, in 1962, gained independence from France.", "answer": "People's Democratic Republic of <b><u>Algeria</u></b> (accept al-Jumh\u016briyya <b><u>al-Jaz\u0101\u02beir</u></b>iyya ad-D\u012bmuqr\u0101\u1e6diyya a\u0161-\u0160a\u02bfbiyya; accept R\u00e9publique <b><u>alg\u00e9rienne</u></b> d\u00e9mocratique et Populaire)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Jean-Pierre Boyer was an early president of this country, the site of an event that was the subject of a 1938 book by C.L.R. James. This country's non-German Sans-Souci Palace was the main residence of its only king, Henri Christophe. Charles Leclerc deported a rebel in this country, which was the subject of the book <em>The Black Jacobins</em>. 1804 brought an end to a revolution in this country led by Toussaint L\u2019Ouverture. For the point, name this island nation, the only state in history established by a successful slave revolt.", "answer": "Republic of <b><u>Haiti</u></b> (accept R\u00e9publique d'<b><u>Ha\u00efti</u> </b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "On the advice of Terentii Shtykov, the territory of this modern nation was occupied for three years by the Soviet Civil Administration. This nation's forces captured the USS <em>Pueblo</em> research vessel off the coast of Ryo Island after suspecting correctly it was being used to spy on this country. A 2019 Summit between the U.S. and this nation hosted in Hanoi ended after a request to destroy the Yongbyon nuclear facility was refused by minister Ri Yong-ho. The term \"Little Rocket Man\" was used by Donald Trump to refer to, for the point, what East Asian nation's leader, Kim Jong-Un?", "answer": "<b><u>North Korea</u></b> (or <b><u>Democratic People's Republic of Korea</u></b> or <b><u>DPRK</u></b>; or <b><u>Choson</u></b>-minjujuui-inmin-konghwaguk)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Members of this group plotted to kill everyone at 10050 Cielo Drive, including Steven Parent and Jay Sebring. This group's leader advocated for an ecological belief system called ATWA, or \"Air, Trees, Water, Animals and All The Way Alive.\" This group, which operated at Spahn Ranch, was exposed when Susan Atkins told of their killings to another inmate. Members of this group named Linda Kasabian and Tex Watson were among those who committed the Tate\u2013LaBianca murders. For the point, name this cult which found secret messages in Beatles songs like \"Helter Skelter.\"", "answer": "The <b><u>Family</u></b> (accept The <b><u>Manson</u></b> Family; accept the <b><u>Manson</u></b>s; accept answers indicating the followers of Charles <b><u>Manson</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}